Christian

Kane

Texas A&M Computer Science Student

Personal Info

Email

christiankane@tamu.edu

Phone

832-364-7271

Address

11902 Foxburo Dr Houston, TX 77065

GitHub

https://github.com/ChristianRossKane

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/christian-kane-845702177/

Website

tx.ag/ckane

Skills

Written and Verbal Communication

Problem Solving

Programming

Mathematics

Agile Methodologies

Public Speaking

React.js

Languages/Frameworks

C++	****
Heroku	****
GitHub	****
Python	****
Java	****
PSQL	****
HTML/CSS	****
Ruby on Rails	****

I managed to complete my entire degree in 3 years with an above average GPA; while this did not allow for me to gather much experience through internships, it is a testament to how truly willing I am to *learn and work with diligence* under difficult constraints.

Education

2019-08 - present

Computer Science, Bachelor of Science

Texas A&M University, College Station (GPA, 3.647)

 Expected to graduate May '22, 6 semesters total, with a BS in Computer Science and a Minor in Mathematics.

Work History

2021-08

Peer Teacher

- 2022-01

Texas A&M University, College Station, TX

- · Helped facilitate undergraduate programming labs:
 - o Worked 6 hours per week with a heavy courseload
 - Assisted in programming regarding relational databases, API queries, etc.
- Held office hours for core undergraduate CS classes:
 - Offered advice as an upperclassman
 - o Worked with dozens of undergraduate students per week
 - · Assisted in programming assignments
 - Learned many soft-skills

Projects

2021-08

Team Leader

- 2021-12

The Aggie Nickwork Website

tx.ag/nickwork

- Acted as the Team Leader
- Developed website for The Aggie Nickwork, a student organization at Texas A&M
- Used Ruby on Rails and Agile / Scrum Methodologies

2021-01

Backend Developer

- 2021-05

CAKAO Movies

cakao.herokuapp.com

- · Acted as the lead Backend Developer
- · Used API calls to:
 - Recommend films / shows based on searches and a watchlist
 - o Display showtimes for films in your area

Courses

2021-08

Software Engineering

- Senior elective meant to emulate a true software-development environment
- · Learned and practiced Agile and Scrum methodologies
- Learned the Ruby on Rails Framework
- Employed CI/CD with GitHub and Heroku Pipelines
- · Grade Earned: A